OLAYIWOLA OLAOLUWA ABIODUN

Ibadan

081-846-54274 /07011639676

olaoluwaowolabi12@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Detail-oriented Quality Control Analyst well-versed in qualitative and quantitative analysis techniques. Demonstrated knowledge of scientific principles and strong background in collecting and analyzing quality measures and making recommendations for process and quality improvements.

Responsible Foreman with excellent project oversight, team management and blueprint interpretation skills coupled with more than 2 years of experience. Achieves project milestones and adheres to deadlines and quality standards.

SKILLS

- Adept at performing analysis
- Sampling
- Materials inspection
- Correction action planning
- Sound quality management techniques
- Materials inspections
- Sampling

WORK HISTORY

ASST. PRINCIPAL EXECUTIVE OFFICER 02/2022 to 01/2023 MINISTRY OF HEALTH, Ibadan (NYSC Service Year)

- Responsible in assisting the PEO (Principal Executive Officer) in carried out executive duties.
- Carried out day-to-day duties accurately and efficiently
- Assist in carried out administrative duties such as writing of memo, promotion and clerical activities,
- Used Microsoft word and other software tools to create documents to build communication skill.
- Collaborated with team members to achieve target results

QUALITY ASSURANCE TRAINEE

06/2020 to 2021

- GB Foods, Lagos
- Provided regular updates to team leadership on quality metrics, communicating consistency problems or production deficiencies with quality and production leadership.
- Monitored product standards and quality-control programs.
- Collected and analyzed activity data and initiated, developed and recommended improvements to systems, processes and procedures to increase productivity and reduce cost.

- Performed standard inspection of first article, first pallet and random sampling inspection to standards.
- Routinely tested products to align temperature, specifications and ingredient levels with best practices and quality standards.
- Halted production line in case of major non-compliance of specifications, standards or quality discovered during inspection process.
- Fixed down time issues during my shift effectively to increase productivity and boost workflows.
- Completed deviation forms and recorded findings of inspection process, collaborating with quality team members and department managers to implement procedural remedies.

QUALITY ASSURANCE INTERN 02/2018 to 02/2019 GB Foods (Gino Tomatoes) Industrial Training Placement, Lagos.

- Providing confidence in company product.
- Collection of different samples.
- Provided regular updates to team leadership on quality metrics, communicating consistency problems or production deficiencies with quality and production leadership.
- Routinely tested products to align temperature, specifications and ingredient levels with best practices and quality standards.
- Promoted adherence to quality standards by educating production operators on quality control.
- Kept inspection journals and daily summary logs as required.
- Inspected, verified and documented quantifiable characteristics of finished goods, comparing against customer specifications and company quality standards to achieve acceptable product.
- Created and collaborated in implementation and maintenance of customer complaint log, control plans, work and inspection instructions, local procedures and visual aids and samples.
- Developed monthly, end-of-quarter and other statistical reports, including analysis for leadership team and for quality improvement program outcomes studies.
- Determined overall product quality by accurately conducting and evaluating various OA tests.

DATA ANALYST

01/2017 to 11/2017

National Population Commission, Lagos

- Enlightening and awareness to people on importance of birth certificate.
- Mapping of distribution of birth certificate materials for easy accessibility in each area.
- Covering all areas within stipulated time and giving adequate report on job.
- Coordinated statistical data analysis, design, and information flow.
- Created various Excel documents to assist with pulling metrics data and presenting them to give concise understanding of best placement for needed resources.
- Participated in requirements meetings and data mapping sessions to understand business needs.

• Corrected any data entry error to prevent later issues such as duplication or data degradation.

INVENTORY ANALYST/CONSTRUCTION FOREMAN 05/2014 to 10/2016 Sana Group Construction, Lagos

- Responsible for managing the overall functioning of the store.
- Take care of the day to day operations of the store and ensures maximum profitability for the store.
- Studied movement of goods to identify gaps in efficiency and other areas needing improvement.
- Used analytical models & analysis to create and maintain key performance metrics.
- Coordinated efficient storage areas to optimize materials movements and minimize labor hours.
- Worked with vendor representatives to resolve damaged shipments and item shortages, protecting company interests and financial targets.
- Boosted inventory and recordkeeping accuracy by conducting thorough inspections and comparing shipment contents with documentation.

EDUCATION

Higher National Diploma: Microbiology, **07/2021 Yaba College of Technology Nigeria** - Yaba Lagos

Ordinary National Diploma: Science Laboratory Technology, **07/2018 Yaba College of Technology** - Yaba Lagos, Nigeria

Diploma: Desktop Publishing, **05/2014**Larrykins Concept – Lagos

Leaving Certificate (S.S.C.E): WASSCE, **05/2013 Gbagada Senior Grammar School** - Gbagada, Lagos

First School Leaving Certificate: 04/2006 Odunlade Primary School - Lagos